[Music]
you
he's beating again
but I was bought
check
all right
[Music]
[Applause]
you
[Music]
here I just don't know what to do I got
a private box video been raised
I have Fujitsu Internet the cloud
no it's just faster before I don't know
like do they throttle you if you stream
why is this going red
I don't even know okay it's dropping
frames it doesn't have upload bandwidth
Oh much upload bandwidth streams good
now ah cool
is it there's my dad garbage it's better
to have my own cloud now not that
garbage upload it still lagging if it's
still lagging I just give up alright
alright am i stupid y'all hang on let me
login down here I'm logging into my
phone so hopefully I can get the chat on
my phone you know
good yes as a touch bar
request SMS oh no I get as a mess no
okay
Oh lovely oh god I hate when it lags all
right now can I get the Arden get the
chat on here Oh
stream chat okay now try saying
something hello
touch bar is a meme oh yes okay
so let's pause this to save bandwidth
perfect I feel like we got a setup going
now
alright so where was I with twitch s
yeah see I can read you I can read you
things on my phone I don't like that I
can't really see my own stream and go to
OBS and I can see it there's me hello
I'm in a private box you can tell them
I'm in the cloud cuz it's all wait
talking is hard though it's weird I
haven't talked in a long time stuck in
this cloud for a while
I do watch myself there I have a problem
you know some people are addicted to
crack cocaine I'm addicted to Maris so
this is what the new new mod that I
added
made it much slower like cookie so the
reason it made that move it's because
the value function now values of a lag
is okay as long as it's not like she lag
is a couple of seconds it shouldn't lag
I just don't do that okay so this is a
very slow value function
when I remove that well how much faster
it's a bit fast so I just legal moves
count but it's not any better
let's read the code to Python chess
deckers so in that Wikipedia thing where
it talks about chess evaluation
functions they usually talk material
mobility King safety center control
doubled backwards and isolated pawns
hotel Wi-Fi test calm
whoever books your hotels what I live on
the cloud gross deep learning the scam
Center control but what is hotel Wi-Fi
test calm I was googling metro station
yes my lease is by there well not a
hotel
loving the cloud
yeah I looked at that project Euler
thing with the hexagon so hard we could
try to do it I also know if project
Euler wants me streaming their like
chess I can stream their cuz no one
owns chess but I respect project Euler I
know they don't like when you would
answers online some material mobility
that might be pretty decent let's see if
we can figure out a way to speed up
legal moves
I'm going to turn off the numb of nose
you've explored
I'm monotonic in fractional seconds new
in version 3.7 watch
okay
no but see now it explores a lot more
moves let's see that took seven seconds
wow what a long time to move
all right should be right out for beta
search alpha beta pruning twitch
guys if we get too many people in the
twitch then he won't be like chill I
don't know I mean I live in the cloud
now I don't know if I should stream back
to earth from the cloud everything's so
quiet here yeah I was disappointed with
the brave I tried very peaceful are you
so far I happen using Safari though that
actually works
okay
we're gonna get a string this isn't that
no I can like convert the board into
like n
I have some stuff about this in state
just say board got serialize thank you
interesting way that that's well then
does include the turn right
turn castling Park episode squared half
of Glock and it'll move number right
cool when the full move number does that
matter
Aisling rights are important
EP square
cool that's pretty good
so now what we want to do is we want
them you always based on that self-doubt
mimo subkey faster
don't even know that actually might be
slower another thing called LRU cache
let's play it
let's play it with the new addition to
the value function
okay it likes to open like that
what are you guys talking about this is
a pleasant stream there's only love in
the cloud okay all we have is love you
guys want to play chess I'll commit it
you guys can ply write that wrapper
nicer
it moves queen out
you can see what's thinking down here
I'll move this
bro don't you know about now moving your
queen I'm gonna defend that pawn let's
go there we're tagging this Queen now
it's exploring like to apply deep I do
think we are gonna need alpha-beta
pruning okay I mean you put me in check
so at least I can't take his queen will
block the check with the night no if we
block the check with a night he can just
take it back and I'll double up my pawns
let's go here and then we'll take with
the night he takes it should be a stupid
law because he were just was official
there's a stream quality good oh you
really gotta think about that one knows
Tommy just lost a bishop I think
now most always queen
I'm trying a little bit harder chest so
the calmer here in this private box
there are other processes constantly you
know thrashing around I always get some
King safety here it was a little bug
down
if you shouldn't be moving as Queen he
developed none of his pieces
traditionally when you think of Chas you
think this is terrible chess so really
good enough chess player to like exploit
the bad moves that other people make you
know I'm saying
okay let's move in with an attack
you know canceling doesn't take two
turns it just takes a turn to update the
thing
I know that good at chess yeah but I'm
better than put just it's also thinking
for a long time now this guy's just
moving as Queen everywhere there's some
new bad I'm reminded again why
streaming is exhausting and the
conversations here are exhausting so
peaceful in the clouds look at how white
everything is it's beautiful
Connect which glut chest to a powerful
cloud I mean I could put it on a on a
box with more course but really probably
the idea would be to like get a real
evaluation function here
I think according to his evaluation
function he's beating me notice how it's
looking and saying negatives their
reality this is terrible chess
hmm
thank God you guys are really exhausting
thoughts on Jordan Peterson all talk of
anything remotely culture war-related is
band dad forever the culture war was the
dumbest thing that I ever spent any time
thinking about
I'll say I forgot how exhausting
streaming to you guys was and reading
that chat I'm just playing a peaceful
game of chess against my computer which
isn't very good yes all right so it's
exploring like 5,000 notes it has kind
of a shitty value function I'm going to
move Queen d5
I can't move Queen d5 there's a bishop
in the way I also can't move Queen da
Queen da would be checkmate though I
agree
all right let's you know you're gonna
bait him no because if he takes that
with the night then if you took there
with the pawn it would be checkmate but
mm-hm go here let him take the bishop
now he admits um winning yeah queen d8
was checkmate but when
Oh today I already uh did I move that
bishop recently alright mate and one
unless he moves you can see over here
how its evaluating stuff
oh my god wait what that was actually
he's really good
their only choice is to move there
well guys really bad Jess yeah
travels
don't think I lost
it's the head that was really not bad or
I'm just that terrible
pen is mine
oh I did go from winning or losing
according to twitch s you're right
there's no those chests I call things
where does one a night didn't I
thank you thank you for subscribing
how's he threatening my queen standing
my queen
how much is a subscription things like
that TV stupid hanky stupid
she's gone from the pawn next to the
castle on the left
it's Batum but come on free night take
your free night bro
mmm good lord I don't know
this guy doesn't think a lot of moves in
advance look I'm winging again take that
toward your chest
Oh guys I'm in the cloud
I can move at the speed of cloudless I'm
in check our line
I'm no king safety
it was move there yeah
we take
shouldn't move that stupid night don't
know why I did that wasn't gonna take it
no stupid debate him howl da dick Cathal
da
yeah boy
mhmmm am I gonna get checkmated I feel
like I'm gonna get checkmated wait if I
go there I lose if I go there he was a
queen there and I lose I can see only
those I can go though I just lost oh my
god nobody beat me I can't move the
night I'm in check I think the only wait
do I have any legal move except for Ji
Won
if I lost I have no legal move beside g1
right
I can't block jack I can't take the bash
up yeah that's my only move I let's see
if it doesn't the only will move no but
I lose because he was the queen it was
the queen to cheat oh where he's stupid
g2 was checkmate
I mean is it doesn't matter now okay so
I can't move there I can't move there
well no but no he's an idiot cuz now I
can go there that was dumb he had me
it had me
checkmate
well
stretched as a woman alright so it had
me be I don't understand why it didn't
see the check man I should have seen it
okay
okay so first off this is poorly written
nice you want to learn flask is flask
faster well it is faster but part of the
reason why I actually has less to do
with the evaluation function what do you
do with the effect evaluation function
has
about 3,000 per second put that add it
back in it's about twice as fast and if
I go to test three what tool do I don't
learn to use flasks
no I'm gonna code openings I don't a
stack oh look I want to be able to beat
me my node isn't your kind of in the
cloud guys the cloud say I like I like
my laptops I can look at myself when I
do that the cloud the cloud so we can't
go three depths that's right
like this is kind of the same logic
what I'm doing life advising streams
anymore
should be correct
can I give you an estimate on when shits
gonna happen yo you guys ever heard
about February let me tell you what is
gonna happen
never
in everywhere yeah yeah
that better way to write this oh no what
time is it in the cloud and times in the
cloud time zero zero like you want to
type date what date is it in the cloud
you mean
get brows I don't know we're watching
right now say Stevie Tom please 51
people or not people it's time zero in
the cloud
hmmm this might be the wrong this might
be the wrong logic
yeah the turn
Oh God halt
yeah be down resolve can't just say this
maybe this time either then a little
evening
that's right
take one movie advance go high weird
time
stupid
how's it they both want to force a draw
in that situation one day I can clearly
see the draw coming right
I don't understand mom thinking enough
was in advance okay so if I've depth to
I search my move and then my opponents
both depth three okay well at least know
my could we've refactored it so we can
write alpha beta pruning negative next
max well if maximizing player negative
max pay equals max a
that's a rat if a is greater than or
equal to B then break this is all the
since this is easy I only left exactly
why this little split
right this the a cutoff be
no weed in the class
maximum recursion depth exceeded
oh you see the problem
let's put this here that's faster
quality minimax service who loves
minimax or alpha beta
think about why this works minimum score
that the maximizing player is assured of
maximize player need not consider
further descendant of this note all
right let's think about why this is
correct
oh yeah
okay I play one more game
it really likes moving that Queen out
fast I don't know what in chess is
supposed to discourage that but it's a
general rule of thumb not to move your
queen out fast develop your minor pieces
don't okay I just do that there's
down a bishop that was upsetting me
stupid mm my pawns protected
oops take that pawn now need to focus
just gonna take my rock
doesn't take that ponds fine we take his
pawn from you know the Queen - now all
my queen
no I know
well that's okay so let's think about
that so you're right that's why yeah I
guess it would wouldn't do that if it
could see more moves in advance but a
camp because it would see like moves in
advance that I'll develop my pieces and
it'll do
it won't do
straight queens of wands
turn the fork does it no the fork
you know the fork
and sleep on
no I can't take that
I was just so stupid okay blunder
tonight blunder on the check
oh my god so dumb so dumb
flus all right
I mean it got better at the end there
let's let's not give it a max Jack let's
just say if V dot count is greater than
10,000 you got count down and this isn't
actually very good
yeah see that's why it's not good chess
seven see what we get
now okay so the thing is called
acquiescence search
Christmas search typically is a value
many Mikes game trees
interesting position it's to a greater
depth activity
Hey
a fan running off I don't know what I'm
going to go to that people spot it's
like never gonna finish it and now we're
going to finish it
yeah I've written all these things
before the bet was the bell of my friend
was that I couldn't write something that
could beat me a chess within a day like
honestly my time here is it's not really
exploring any position that's right oh
there we go it got to seven
oh look it found oh oh look at found e4
oh wow a good wolf yeah I know don't
have the norm against new folks I have
No
let's see if it still makes those stupid
Queen moves
in this book
okay
Cyril starts to play game just like
toilet papers games are measured implies
well this is really thrashing my
computer here so we're only exploring
like 2000 positions per second
yeah
so modern chess engines are exploding
things
Wailea way faster than I look at still
making these stupid Queen moves can't
see bad it multiple ply
yeah okay so alpha-beta order depends a
lot
in order deepen a yeah
well I understand why it's called
quiescent this makes sense extra search
is just called a quiescent search
one possible approach to forward pruning
is beam so much okay
so I've heard this before well that's
taking too long let's just say here just
depth one hey depth is less than three
or def 307 but realize that that will
like waste things make it right beam
search pretty easily
okay more game let's play improve to
twitch chess this one should be very
good except it should take a long time
that's the problem
your Python chest at any closing value
functions
yeah almost
is it quiet
well that's a normal movie the name take
a real people move
that's a much more reasonable chess
position now all right
actually I don't think that is a people
move cuz that'll people move is that a
real opening chests our common lady like
the table
now it moves the same piece twice on the
opening this is stupid and this is
really slow annoying to play against
you know it explores a lot of nodes now
that's not good
so what
you know get this thing this is a system
I'm gonna play this game yeah
all right so just doing it back to
something that's playable
so what are our options here and I say
vices itself
well doesn't update the board
I think it used to play really fast that
was okay yeah the value functions
garbage it can't explore many nodes
you're probably right beam search beam
search just prunes off a lot of
quickly
and this value functions are swaying
back and forth like crazy
I'm the queen
clean runs away with the works besides a
Kevin I
the worst game of chess I've ever seen
played move the King 1 square yeah we
could rewrite it and see to make it
faster promise this chest thing is an
inherently Python thing with black
barely moved any of their pieces yeah I
don't know were you writing in C doesn't
sound fun that might be it for twitch
chess the answer is you probably need C
you know it's just Google number apply
chess versus raid I don't write it and
see that's not shitty
five ply
right now it's only thinking two to five
line
sports pipe I through install pi PI
yeah I know it'll be faster in any
language except for Python but I only
know how to code Python why is Python
swap so apparently if I can get this
thing to work at five ply
that's stupid class the state class is
kind of a stupid class okay I mean
I only need like three packages I don't
really need torch
that one I have less hope for my work
using on by cerium let's function we're
gonna need that are there see your fish
alright so I think we can actually make
it beam search quite easy
if I press faster
we trained for that oh look at that pipe
I speed up five high school fast
I don't understand why I like that craps
there that's different
I thought Python oh is it for some
reason
if he's not greater than C if it is fast
I think also it helped the way that I
pruned okay let's see if now we can go
five play deep no Popeyes is like five X
faster Wow that pie pie speed bros okay
[Music]
whoops yeah
depth greater than search what fast is
that oh yeah I got to do with pie pie
I don't know what you're asking what you
want to ask how to learn things and how
to be good at things what are you asking
me for go do things step one
don't be a noob step 2 commit to not
being a noob for the rest of your life
are you committed to not being a noob
for the rest of your life I commit to
these things you know do you guys see
the board really okay now it's thinking
five plies deep according to that reddit
post if you think five plies deep you
are Chazz master Dan at college I was
pretty stupid
you gotta commit your life to not be in
a noop a lot of people go through life
thinking about you know what other
people think about them whether they're
gonna get married or whether they're
gonna have kids
or you know all who they're gonna
disappoint or all that man you
gotta just put it out of your mind and
commit to not being a newt not for
anybody else but for yourself because if
you can't commit to not being a noob for
yourself then I don't know what you're
doing with your life
okay this is a decent see where it moves
the night it didn't move the night it
just put me under check oh my god I
messed up he can now take that thing
with his queen no not anymore
that was stupid can I now take his night
oh no it can't because I'm in check okay
I don't see anything wrong with that
do I play rated chess regularly not
really what I do is like a 1500 I played
on chess comm 1500 and I like at 1300 of
let's 1500 for longer games I don't know
like I still don't trust that the
machine is any good at all so I'm not
like trying you know that hard like if
it starts to really surprise me then we
got to play a lot harder wait a second
but I take your knight you lose a knight
how did you not see that it thinks it's
winning right now now it thinks it's
losing how did I not see me taking that
night
why does it think it's beating me oh I
didn't think it was beating me no look
here I thought it was beating me
position to move the night there I
probably wasn't a good move
chestnut column collects data from a lot
of noobs Oh you SFIL a lot of data from
a lot of moves is
I can't castle
that piece is under attack
on top of my pawns is fine I don't know
why everyone always writes up time like
that what I think that is
it thinks it's back to beating me
oh god wait it really like might be
if you have better ttv young having a
okay at least you can't threaten me
like that anymore
see I really I haven't been able to
castle
yeah I enjoy thinking five moves ahead
there
it was a pawn
hmm
I mean check if you want
oh my god you just want a bishop he's
pretty good
he's pretty good now that's guys I know
yeah to be honest he cut yeah sure who
came to see - yeah you're right
I just lost my patient didn't I this
guy's not bad
you won't exchange doesn't know about
the value of that position to that poem
you won't exchange his night for it
he's pretty good it's pretty player you
know
oops
what he's gonna do
that was stupid it could have taken your
castle but could it have
remember that but this isn't okay
they're gone all right what stink mmm
no he has the knight attacking at tail
woman check Wow okay I'm in check again
great it was you know and I was lower
because I'm an idiot
Wow such a good player such a good
player Oh does it know how to mate
why don't you check me to me it one firm
is pretty good I think we can even
probably remember that 10 is we can say
actually put it 7 game baby play one
more game let's really try my best I
think it beat me I think that this
program can consistently beat me well I
know one more game let's go I put the
search depth out to out to 7 it will
lower the beam
No
the one life advice anymore whatever
those are pretty good settings alright
let's try it let's see if it can play
the Queen okay
right now I wanted to play the Queen
opening let's see if I can play the
Queen opening it's the same move
it beeped me
so what my friend said when we made the
bet was he thinks that I could learn to
exploit its advantages like since I
coded it I can know exactly what to look
for
okay like I know this crap cuz I can't
if I go there I'm going there is
actually fun I think let's go there
what I work on I don't know okay again
this is similar this is the same way the
last game played I went there I forgot
about I don't know
well er girlfriend fear at oculus
no no this is very similar to how the
last games laid out
give it I don't know I don't think I can
think five moves deep or something it
loses the night again I could do that
same thing last time
if you thought it was winning and now it
thinks it's losing okay I'm in the same
position I'll have this pinned bishop
okay let's I'm a human I'm supposed to
be able to like you know learn from
experience let's get the bishop on
pinned
I know it one last time that's why I'm
learning from experience like a human
Kapaun
I still have not succeeded and unpinning
there
it's gonna move the look there I think
ya likes that move
but if I move the Queen right there it's
fine
stupid
I'm gonna do that
just traded or work for okay now I don't
think it's a depth problem now I think
it's a value function problem um so you
guys see with the value functions coded
you can improve measure taken with the
Queen they did
how can it check Mamie
explain to me the checkmate that I
missed
and queens under attack
about pieces
what it Forks my bro I hate when it
Forks your
worked my
okay let's actually be smart the endgame
I want to at least say that I beat it
once so I just got my forked again
hate when she gets for gonna take my
poem
it's not even AI you don't get really
his guys want a life last my friend I'll
give you a life lesson is Moore's law
it's it's Moore's law just you know how
I can be crushed by this thing that's
written in Python not Kraft I said we're
we're similar in skill meat which chess
are similar in skill to fork my shirt
again hey barks my nice fun um who
told you more laws dead are you
listening to people from Intel telling
you about how Intel's dead that's what
I've heard I've heard Intel's dead all
right
Iraq I don't even get anything back bye
bye Brooke I thought I got out of it but
no byrock Wow I resigned yeah I know I
know it's good guys it's really good a
chance okay everybody else go try to
casually play it and beat me
go Charlie casually play it in this kind
of like time time control format
Oh
oh oh look the tricked me you see how it
tricked me right
oh yeah draw no no no it's a draw that
was actually a draw um that was a draw I
repeated the same move three times in a
row no okay I I would say that it's a
draw um I would say that twitch chess is
about on par with me I would consider
the bed over I'm not gonna waste time
racing this but you can play with the
value function no I mean it only lost
cuz it doesn't like it can't see enough
moves in advance to move those pawns
down you can fix that with like
acquiescence search like it go deep kind
of thing but I really actually don't
know why I did that it should have saw
that state but um I don't know cool guys
I consider twitch chess kind of finished
to which
brought up the GG folks GG Wow 90 people
saw me got beat by my AI so yeah you can
uh - anybody playing along at home try
it out I'm gonna actually remove some of
those requirements move this into
serialize
I should leave
they have won anything all right
what I mean that's probably after time
control I was playing
listen to interplay yeah plenty of room
movement nice - yes let's just buy that
right now
cool
[Applause]
secondly sure that works
I don't ask
and I do strike through
no neural network
I would never rinse cake scammer
call
what it hasn't came dormancy and
quiescence some weird about embryos
senescence all degenerates
twitch twitch there we go yeah well you
know that was twitch s and the t's
finished to look thank you all for
watching
but that tastes finished too and now
there's no more tea so you guys know
that there's two food groups in the
cloud there's our ramen and their sushi
those are the two cloud food groups so
good you know I had ramen for lunch you
know when I hit the computer whoo that's
loud I'm sorry guys can you start
reverse engineering for life I love
ramen well I'm in the cloud whoa yo is
his team den this is team 10 oh
please subscribe I need your money
I love money money's my favorite thing
except for
no I just love money winning
maybe I how do you get recruited as you
check ball knotted by anything I don't
buy anything to see my balcony my god my
balcony
let's go out of my balcony
you guys is a dominoes outside there's
Domino's is in the cloud more coding in
C++
no we in the cloud